{
  "status": "success",
  "data": [
    {
      "question": "‘Look before you leap’ is an example of________sentence",
      "answer": "imperative",
      "moreDetails": "",
      "arr": ["imperative", "assertive", "Exclamatory", "interrogative"]
    },
    {
      "question": "They are playing out side is a/ an_______ sentence",
      "answer": "Affirmative",
      "moreDetails": "(If a sentence starts with subject (I, we, you, they, he, she, it or names of\r\nanything)\r\nis an assertive sentence\r\nimperative - starts with verb)\r\neg: Have a cup of tea\r\ncome here",
      "arr": ["Affirmative", "Imperative", "interrogative", "exclamatory"]
    },
    {
      "question": "Pick the simple sentence from the following",
      "answer": "He calls me daily",
      "moreDetails": "",
      "arr": [
        "He calls me daily",
        "He called me but I couldn’t go",
        "when he called me I was sleeping",
        "none of above"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "“Inspite of better treatment the patient died” is a_____ sentence",
      "answer": "simple",
      "moreDetails": "",
      "arr": ["simple", "compound", "complex", "compound complex"]
    },
    {
      "question": "I went market and bought vegetable is a____ sentence",
      "answer": "compound",
      "moreDetails": "",
      "arr": ["compound", "complex", "simple", "compound complex"]
    },
    {
      "question": "As you are already here you can surely do the work",
      "answer": "complex",
      "moreDetails": "(How to identify simple, compound, complex sentence)\r\nSimple sentence - Gerund (V1+ing), inspite of, despite, too...to, enough, after\r\n\r\ndue to etc....\r\nCompound - and, but, or, so etc...\r\nComplex - if, when, which, while, as, so that, that etc.\r\neg: He is so strong that he can lift that box alone",
      "arr": ["complex", "compound", "simple", "compound complex"]
    },
    {
      "question": "“Being tired he fell asleep” convert the sentence into compound",
      "answer": "He was tired and fell asleep",
      "moreDetails": "",
      "arr": [
        "He was tired and fell asleep",
        "He is tired and fall asleep",
        "tiredness makes him asleep",
        "when he was tired fell asleep"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Change the following sentence into complex (The Earth is round, we can prove)",
      "answer": "we can prove that the Earth is round",
      "moreDetails": "",
      "arr": [
        "we can prove that the Earth is round",
        "The Earth is round so we can prove",
        "The Earth is round and we prove it",
        "The Earth is round but we can prove"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "‘He worked hard but failed’ change into simple",
      "answer": "Inspite of hard work he failed",
      "moreDetails": "",
      "arr": [
        "Inspite of hard work he failed",
        "He worked hard and failed",
        "He worked so hard and failed",
        "All of above"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Pick the Complex sentence",
      "answer": "John has a Piano which plays well",
      "moreDetails": "Primary and modal auxiliaries\r\nprimary auxiliary(11): is, am, are, was, were, do, does, did, has, have, had\r\nModal auxiliary(13): will, would, shall, should, can, could, may, might, must,\r\nought to, used to, need, dare",
      "arr": [
        "John has a Piano which plays well",
        "John plays piano well",
        "John has a piano and it plays well",
        "John has a piano but it doesn't play well"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "My father______ go for a walk daily",
      "answer": "used to",
      "moreDetails": "",
      "arr": ["used to", "will", "can", "will"]
    },
    {
      "question": "______You move a bit?",
      "answer": "would",
      "moreDetails": "",
      "arr": ["would", "can", "will", "may"]
    }
  ]
}
